thelines.com 2019-03-31

# Privacy Policy | The Lines

## CATENA MEDIA PRIVACY AND COOKIES POLICY

At Catena Media **(“Catena Media”, “we”, “us”)** , we process personal data about our customers and visitors on our websites **(“you”)**. We make efforts to handle your personal data with care, keep it secure and comply with data protection laws.

[Website] **(“Webiste”)** is a part of the Catena Media group, engaged in lead generation online and content publishing regarding financial information and services. Catena Media group has its headquarters in Malta with subsidiaries in several countries worldwide.

* * *

  1. **Who is responsible for looking after your personal data?**

Catena Operations Ltd having its registered address Quantum Place, Triq ix-Xatt, Ta´Xbiex, Gzira, Malta GZR 1052, is principally responsible for looking after your personal data (your Data Controller). Data Controller means the company that determines the means and purposes of processing of personal data.

You should be aware that although we are principally responsible for looking after your personal data, information may be held in databases which can be accessed by third parties. When accessing your personal data, all third parties will comply with the standards set out in this Policy. 

Catena Media is a group of companies with subsidiaries in several countries, for example in the European Union, Australia, Japan and the USA.

  2. **What personal data do we process?**

We may process the following personal data about you:

    * Name
    * Data of birth
    * Email address
    * Password
    * IP address
    * Location data
    * Website usage
    * Gender
    * Age
    * Occupation
    * Personal preferences and opinions

  3. **What do we use your personal data for and when do we process your personal data?**

Catena Media will collect information directly from you when you use our services or visit our websites. 

We use your personal data to:

    * send out promotional emails relating to products and services. See also Section 6 below on Direct marketing.
    * analyze information in our systems and databases to improve the way we run our business and websites according to user preferences, to provide a better service and user experience. 
    * Improve and target advertisements that you receive from us. 
    * register you for a chat forum or community, if we make available, in which you can provide comments. 
    * meet or exercise any of our legal obligations or rights

  4. **Who do we share your personal data with?**

We work with many third parties, to help manage our business and deliver services, and Catena Media will disclose personal data to those third parties under the following circumstances:

    * **Marketing Communications.** Unless users opt-out from receiving Catena Media marketing materials upon registration, Catena Media may email users about products and services that Catena Media believes may be of interest to them. If you wish to opt-out of receiving marketing materials from Catena Media you may do so by following the unsubscribe link in the email communications, by going to your account settings (if applicable) or contacting us using the contact information below.
    * **Third-Party Service Providers.** We may share your personal data, which may include your name and contact information (including email address) with our authorized service providers that perform certain services on our behalf. These services may include fulfilling orders, providing customer service and marketing assistance, performing business and sales analysis, supporting the Website’s functionality and supporting contests, sweepstakes, surveys and other features offered through the Website. We may also share your n personal data with our authorized service providers who process credit card payments. These service providers may have access to personal information needed to perform their functions but are not permitted to share or use such information for any other purpose.
    * **Affiliates in the Catena Media group:** With Catena Media plc or any of its directly or indirectly owned or controlled affiliates in the Catena Media group. Transfers of personal data will be subject to Catena Media intra-group data transfer agreements.

We may also disclose your personal data under the additional circumstances below:

    * **Requiered By Law or to Protect Rights.** When we believe disclosure is appropriate, we may disclose Personally-Identifying Information in connection with efforts to investigate, prevent or take other action regarding illegal activity, suspected fraud or other wrongdoing; to protect and defend the rights, property or safety of Company, our users, our employees or others; to comply with applicable law or cooperate with law enforcement; to enforce our Terms of Use or otheragreements or policies, in response to a subpoena or similar investigative demand, a court order or a request for cooperation from a law enforcement or other government agency; to establish or exercise our legal rights; to defend against legal claims; or as otherwise required by law. In such cases, we may raise or waive any legal objection or right available to us.
    * **Business Transfers; Bankruptcy.** Company reserves the right to transfer all Personally- Identifying Information in its possession to a successor organization in the event of a merger, acquisition, bankruptcy or other sale of all or a portion of Company’s assets. Other than to the extent ordered by a bankruptcy or other court, the use and disclosure of all transferred Personally-Identifying Information will be subject to this Privacy Policy, or to a new privacy policy if you are given notice of that new privacy policy and are given an opportunity to affirmatively opt- out of it. Personally-Identifying Information submitted or collected after a transfer, however, may be subject to a new privacy policy adopted by the successor organization.

  5. **Changing Personally-Identifying Information; Account Termination**

You may at any time review or change your personal data by going to your account settings (if applicable) or contacting us using the contact information below. Upon your request, we will deactivate or delete your account and contact information from our active databases. Such information will be deactivated or deleted as soon as practicable based on your account activity and accordance with our deactivation policy and applicable law. To make this request, either go to your account settings (if applicable) or contact us as provided below. We will retain in our files some Personally-Identifying Information to prevent fraud, to troubleshoot problems, to assist with any investigations, to enforce our Terms of Use and to comply with legal requirements as is permitted by law. Therefore, you should not expect that all your personal data will be completely removed from our databases in response to your requests. Additionally, we keep a history of changed information to investigate suspected fraud with your account.

  6. **Security**

We take the security of your personal data seriously and use reasonable electronic, personnel and physical measures to protect it from loss, theft, alteration or misuse. However, please be advised that even the best security measures cannot fully eliminate all risks. We cannot guarantee that only authorized persons will view your information. We are not responsible for third-party circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures.

We are dedicated to protect all information on the Website as is necessary. However, you are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your Personally-Identifying Information by keeping your password confidential. You should change your password immediately if you believe someone has gained unauthorized access to it or your account. If you lose control of your account, you should notify us immediately.

  7. **Privacy policy changes**

Catena Media may, in its sole discretion, change this Privacy Policy from time to time. Any and all changes to Catena Media’s Privacy Policy will be reflected on this page and the date new versions are posted will be stated at the top of this Privacy Policy. Unless stated otherwise, our current Privacy Policy applies to all information that we have about you and your account. Users should regularly check this page for any changes to this Privacy Policy. Catena Media will always post new versions of the Privacy Policy on the Website. However, Company may, as determined in its discretion, decide to notify users of changes made to this Privacy Policy via email or otherwise. Accordingly, it is important that users always maintain and update their contact information.

  8. **Children**

The Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (“COPPA”) protects the online privacy of children under 13 years of age. We do not knowingly collect or maintain Personally-Identifying Information from anyone under the age of 13, unless or except as permitted by law. Any person who provides personal data through the Website represents to us that he or she is 13 years of age or older. If we learn personal data has been collected from a user under 13 years of age on or through the Website, then we will take the appropriate steps to cause this information to be deleted. If you are the parent or legal guardian of a child under 13 who has become a member of the Website or has otherwise transferred personal data to the Website, please contact Catena Media using our contact information below to have that child’s account terminated and information deleted.

  9. **California privacy rights**

California Civil Code Section 1798.83, also known as the “Shine The Light” law, permits our users who are California residents to request and obtain from us, once a year and free of charge, information about personal dat (if any) we disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year. If applicable, this information would include a list of the categories of the personal data that was shared and the names and addresses of all third parties with which we shared personal data in the immediately preceding calendar year. If you are a California resident and would like to make such a request, please submit your request in writing to our privacy team as listed below.

  10. **Do-Not-Track Policy**

Most web browsers and some mobile operating systems include a Do-Not-Track (“DNT”) feature or setting you can activate to signal your privacy preference not to have data about your online browsing activities monitored and collected. Because there is not yet a common understanding of how to interpret the DNT signal, the Website currently does not respond to DNT browser signals or mechanisms.

  11. **How long do we keep your personal data?**

We will retain your personal data for as long as reasonably necessary for the purposes listed in Section 3 of this Policy. 

In some circumstances we keep your personal data during a certain period to meet for example legal, tax or accounting requirements.

We maintain a data retention policy for personal data in our care. Where your personal data is no longer required we will ensure it is either securely deleted or made anonymous.

  12. **CONTACT**

If you have any questions regarding our Privacy Policy, please contact our Privacy Team at: **privacy@catenamedia.com**

### Cookie Policy

**We use Cookies**

To offer you a full range of functions when you visit our website, recognize your preferences, and make the use of our website more comfortable and convenient, we use “cookies.” 

**What are Cookies?**

A cookie, pixel or similar technology is a small file or information saved on your computer or device when you visit the website. It enables the website to remember your actions and preferences (such as login, language, font size and other display preferences) over a period of time, so you don’t have to keep re-entering them whenever you come back to the site or browse from one page to another. 

**Your options**

By using our website, you agree to the use and storage of cookies on your computer or device.

You can generally view our website without cookies, but certain parts of the website may not work properly or navigating be slower.

If you do not wish cookies to be stored on your computer or device, you can deactivate the relevant option in the system settings of your browser. You can also delete stored cookies in the system settings of your browser at any time. 

More information on how to deactivate or delete cookies can be found here: <https://www.aboutcookies.org/cookie-faq/>. However, please keep in mind that if you do not accept any cookies this may restrict the functionality of our offerings.

**Categories of cookies**

We use cookies for different purposes and with different functions. 

Some cookies are:

  * necessary in technical terms (technical necessity) 
  * stored and used for a certain time period (storage duration)
  * placed and stored by us or a third party (cookie provider).

**Technical necessity**

Cookies that are technically: 

  * **Necessary:** We use certain cookies because they are strictly necessary in order for the website and its functions to work properly. These cookies are automatically placed on your computer or device when you access the website or a certain function, unless you have set your browser to reject cookies. 
  * **Not necessary:** Cookies that are not strictly necessary are placed on your computer or device to improve convenience and performance of our website or save certain settings that you have made. We also use cookies that are not strictly necessary in technical terms to get information on the frequency of use of certain areas of our website, so that we can adapt to your needs and requirements on a more targeted basis.

**Storage duration**

**Session cookies:** Some cookies are only needed for the duration of your website session, so called “session cookies”. They will be erased or become invalid as soon as you leave our website or your current session expires. Session cookies are used, for example, to retain certain information during your session.

**Permanent cookies:** Some cookies are stored for a longer period. For example, it allows to recognize you when you access our website again at a later time and access saved settings. As a result, you can access webpages faster or with greater convenience, for example that you do not need to set certain options again, such as your chosen language. Permanent cookies are automatically deleted after a predefined period. 

**Flow cookies:** These cookies are used for communication between our internal servers within our company group. They are placed on your computer or device when you start navigating the website and deleted after the end of your navigation on the website. Flow cookies are given a unique identification number but does not allow us to draw any conclusions regarding the actual customer or user.

**Cookie providers**

**Provider cookies:** These are cookies are placed by us or the operator of our website, who is commissioned by us.

**Third-party cookies:** “Third-party cookies” are stored and used by other organisations or websites, for example Web analytics tools. External providers may also use cookies to display advertising or to integrate content from social networks, such as social plugins. For further information on Web analytics tools and measurement of reach, please see below in this cookie policy.

**Use of cookies for Web analytics and reach measurement**

We use Google Analytics, a Web analytics service of Google Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses cookies to identify the frequency of use of certain areas of our website and to identify preferences. The information regarding your use of this website that is generated by the cookie (including your truncated IP address) is transferred to a Google server in the United States and stored there. Google will use this information to analyze your use of the website, compile reports on website activity for us, and perform further services associated with website use and Internet use. Google may also transmit this information to third parties where required by law or to the extent third parties process these data on behalf of Google.

**You can deactivate Google Analytics using a browser add-on if you do not wish the website analysis to take place. You can download the add-on here: https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=.**

This add-on stores “opt-out” information on your device that serves to match up your deactivation of Google Analytics. Please note that this kind of “opt out” only leads to the deactivation of Google Analytics for the device and browser from which the opt out was activated. In addition, you may need to reactivate it if you delete cookies from your device.

Our most common cookies are: 

**Name of cookie** | **Cookie provider** | **Purpose**  
---|---|---  
Google Analytics | Google | This Cookie is placed by Google. It enables our website to learn information about our users’ use of our site, such as the time of visit, the pages viewed, whether the user has visited before and the websites visited prior to visiting ours.  
Facebook Pixel | Facebook | This Cookie is placed by Facebook. It enables our website to measure, optimize and build audiences for advertising campaigns served on Facebook.  
One Signal | One Signal | This Cookie is placed by One Signal. It enables our website to remember that you subscribed to receive push notifications. It also helps us deliver personalized notifications.  
VWO | VWO | This Cookie is placed by VWO. VWO places cookies in end user’s and customer’s browser to identify the user. Cookies do not contain any of your personal data. They may also collect and store information locally on your device, using mechanisms such as browser web storage.  
Hotjar | Hotjar | This Cookie is placed by Hotjar. It collects non-personal information, with the overall aim of providing you with a better website experience, diagnose technical problems and analyze trends.  
Unbounce | Catena Media | Unbounce is a tool that helps us build better landing pages. Unbounce cookies will be used to collect non-personal data that will be used to improve the landing pages and provide a better experience.  
AdWords | AdWords | AdWords is used to enable Google PPC (pay per click) campaigns.  
Double Click | Double Click | Double Click is used for advertisers and to advertise on multiple ad servers.
